## **Michael Sanders**

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **PROFILE**

I'm a creative, passionate, and self-driven software engineer with 10+ years of experience. I strive to write better code every day by focusing on the SOLID design principles and consistency through automation. I also strongly believe in sharing what I've learned with the community through mentoring, writing online articles, and presenting to the public.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Helios Interactive**, Portland — *Sr. Software Engineer*

OCT 2016 - PRESENT

- Architect and implement fullstack, multidisciplinary software solutions for high-stakes, quick turnaround projects.
- Provide professional support to developing software engineers through advice, coaching, and educational opportunities.
- Facilitate twice-weekly, companywide brainstorm meetings to develop ideas in response to customer needs and RFPs.
- Assist with software budgeting and scoping.

## **Axiom Custom Products**, Portland — *Sr. Software Engineer*

NOV 2013 - OCT 2016

- Designed, implemented, and maintained the company's internal project management software.
- Worked with Producers to scope, budget, and implement the software portion of external and internal projects.

## **Rogue Valley Door,** Grants Pass — *Software Engineer*

SEP 2006 - SEP 2008, MAR 2010 - APR 2012

- Turned senior engineer's designs into production-ready code.
- Converted the corporate website from ASP to ASP.NET.

# **Business Owner's Idea Cafe,** Grants Pass — *Jr. Software Engineer*

SUMMERS OF 2003 & 2004

• Created basic PHP page and performed data entry.

### **EDUCATION**

## **Rogue Community College**

SEP 2006 - JUN 2008

3237 SE 119th Ave Portland, OR 97266 (971) 276-7564 michael@pixel-cur.io

### **PRIMARY SKILLS**

C#

Unity 3D

ASP.NET

GIT

VR / AR

CI / CD

**Jenkins** 

Codepipeline

Docker

#### SECONDARY SKILLS

Javascript, Node, CSS, C++, OpenGL, PHP

### PROFESSIONAL OUTREACH

Shader Lesson Plan - 2019 Developed a Unity-focused lesson plan on shaders for beginners. Shared through an online publication.

Shader Tutorial - 2018 Wrote a 7-part, beginner's tutorial for a Unity-based "jelly" shader. Open-sourced the final product.

PIGSquad Talent Talk - 2017 Presented a lightning talk on adding polish to a Unity project during PIGSquad's annual "Talent Talks."

Portland Art Museum - 2015 Helped brainstorm and develop interactive ideas to enhance an upcoming exhibit.